<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The replication to the City of London's plea to the quo warranto brought against their charter by our Sovereign Lord the King in Michaelmas term, 1681</title>
            <author>England and Wales.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 33 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A91652</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">36273492</idno>
  <idno type="VID">150224</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240924557</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R1047</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R200601</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">36273492</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A91652)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 150224)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2236:41)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The replication to the City of London's plea to the quo warranto brought against their charter by our Sovereign Lord the King in Michaelmas term, 1681</title>
                  <author>England and Wales.</author>
                  <author>Sawyer, Robert, Sir, 1633-1692.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Attorney-General.</author>
                  <author>London (England). City of London's plea to the quo warranto (an information) brought against their charter in Michaelmas term, 1681.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 13 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Benj. Tooke ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCLXXXII [1682]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>In Latin and English.</note>
                  <note>Reply brief, by Attorney-General Robert Sawyer, to the plea published in 1682 under title: The City of London's plea to the quo warranto (an information) brought against their charter in Michaelmas term, 1681.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: [A]² B-D² E1.</note>
                  <note>Incorrectly identified on film as Wing R1074, which is located at reel position 2236:43.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Quo warranto --  England --  London.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">London (England) --  Charters, grants, privileges.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="lat" type="version">
            <pb facs="tcp:150224:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:150224:1"/>
            <head>Dominus Rex versus Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jorem &amp; Communitat. ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>ET predict’ <hi>Robertus Saw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yer</hi> Attorn. dict’ Domini Regis nunc General. qui pro eodem domino Rege nunc in hac parte sequitur quoad Placitum prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fat’ Majoris &amp; Communitat’ ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vium Civitat’ predict’ quoad Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat. Privilg. &amp; Franches. predict’ per ipsos superius clamat’ <hi>(viz.)</hi> ip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sos Majorem &amp; Communitat’ ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves Civitat’ <hi>London.</hi> fore de se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ipsis unum Corpus Corporat’ &amp; Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liticum in re facto &amp; nomine per no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men Majoris &amp; Communitat’ ac Civium Civitat. <hi>London.</hi> ac per idem nomen placitare &amp; implacitari respondere ac responderi superius pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>citat’ pro eodem Dom. Rege nunc dic’ quod per aliqua per prefat’ Majorem &amp; Communitat. ac Cives Civitat. <hi>London.</hi> predict’ superius placitan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>do allegat’ eadem Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Franches. eisdem Majori &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitat’ ac Civibus Civitat’ <hi>London.</hi>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:150224:2"/> predict’ allocari seu adjudicari non debent nec iidem Major &amp; Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitas ac Cives de premis’ in Informac’ predict’ superius specificat’ exonerari debent quia dic’ quod Cives Civit’ <hi>London.</hi> predict’ à tempore cujus contrar’ memor’ homin’ non existit’ non fuer’ corpus corporat’ &amp; politi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cum in re facto &amp; nomine per nomen Majoris &amp; Communitat’ ac Civium Civitat’ <hi>London.</hi> modo &amp; forma prout prefat’ Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit’ <hi>London.</hi> predict’ superius placitando allegaver. Et hoc idem Attorn’ dict’ Dom. Regis nunc General’ pro eodem Dom. Rege nunc pet’ quod inquiratur per patri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am. Et predict’ <hi>Robertus Sawyer</hi> Attorn’ dict’ Dom. Regis nunc Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral’ quoad placitum prefat’ Majo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ris &amp; Communitat’ ac Civium Civit’ <hi>London.</hi> predict’ quoad Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Franches. predict’ per ipsos superius clamat’ <hi>(viz.)</hi> ipsos Majorem &amp; Communitat. ac Cives Civit’ <hi>London.</hi> fore de seipsis u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num corpus corporat’ &amp; politicum in re facto &amp; nomine per nomen Majoris &amp; Communitat’ ac Civium Civitat’ <hi>London.</hi> ac per idem no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men placitare &amp; implacitari respon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dere ac responderi superius placitat’
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:150224:2"/> ulterius dic’ quod per aliqua per pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fat’ Majorem &amp; Communitat’ ac Cives Civit’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perius placitando allegat. Eedem Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Franches. eisdem Majori &amp; Communitat’ ac Civibus Civit’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>locari seu adjudicari non debent nec iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives de premiss. in Informatione predict’ superius specificat’ exonerari debent, quia protestando quod Cives ejus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Civitat’ a tempore cujus con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trar’ memor’ homin’ non existit non fuer’ corpus corporat’ &amp; politicum in re facto nomine per nomen Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joris &amp; Communitat’ ac Civium Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit’ <hi>London,</hi> ac per idem nomen per totum tempus illud placitaver’ ac implacitat’ fuerunt responder’ ac res<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pons’ fuer’ &amp; placitare &amp; implaci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tari respondere ac responderi a toto tempore supradict’ ufi fuer’ &amp; con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suever’ prout predict’ Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit’ <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> predict’ superius placitando al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>legaverunt pro placito tamen idem Attorn’ dict’ Dom. Regis nunc Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral’ pro eodem Domino Rege nunc ulterius dic’ quod predict’ Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit’ <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:150224:3"/> predict’ assumentes super se fore corpus corporat’ &amp; politicum ac ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cione inde potestatem &amp; authorita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tem habere ad seipsos insimul convo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cand’ &amp; assembland’ ad bona &amp; salubria leges ordines &amp; ordinac’ o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes legibus &amp; statutis hujus regni <hi>Angl’</hi> minime repugnan’ sive con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trar’ pro meliori regimine &amp; gu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bernac’one Civit’ predict’ ac Civium &amp; inhabitantium ejusdem Civitat’ ac pro conservac’one pacis Dom. Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gis infra Civit’ predict’ iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit’ <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> predict’ sub colore &amp; pretextu inde eorum privatum lucrum &amp; com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modum solum respicien’ contra fidu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciam in corpore corporato &amp; politico per Dom. Regem &amp; Leges hujus regni <hi>Anglie</hi> reposit’ assumpser’ il<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licitam &amp; injustam potestatem &amp; authoritat’ ad denar’ de subdit’ ac ligeis Dom. Regis nunc levand’ ad usum ipsorum Majoris &amp; Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitat’ ac Civium Civitat. <hi>London</hi> predict’ propr’ colore legum sive Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinaco’n’ per ipsos de facto ordinat. &amp; stabilit’ abs{que} aliquo alio Jure Titulo sive Authoritate quibuscun{que} ac in prosecuc’on’ &amp; execuc’on’ hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jusmodi illegalis &amp; injuste potestat’ &amp; authoritat’ per ipsos sic usurpat’
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:150224:3"/> iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves Civitat. <hi>London</hi> predict’ die <hi>Jovis</hi> decimo septimo die <hi>Septem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bris</hi> Anno Regni dict’ Dom. Regis nunc vicesimo sexto in eorum Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ni Concilio adtunc tent’ in Camera <hi>Guihald</hi> Civit. <hi>London</hi> predict’ (viz.) in Paroch’ Sancti <hi>Michae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lis Bassishaw, London,</hi> insimul Assemblat’ fuer’ condider’ &amp; publica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver’ quandam Legem per ipsos de facto inactitat’ pro levac’one seper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alium denar’ summar’ de omnibus sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit’ ac Ligeis Dom. Regis nunc tam liberis quam non liberis hominibus Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit’ predict’ &amp; aliis extraneis ad pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lica Mercata infra Civitat’ predict’ tent’ acceden’ cum victual’ &amp; provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sionibus suis ibidem vendend’ (viz.) de qualibet persona pro quolibet onere equino <hi>Anglice</hi> Horse-load provisi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on’ in aliquod public’ Mercat’ infra Civit’ predict’ per ipsum importat’ ibi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem vendend’ duorum denar’ per di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>em &amp; pro qualibet canistra <hi>Anglice</hi> Dosser provision’ in aliquod Mercat’ predict’ ibidem vendend’ importat’ unius denar’ per diem &amp; pro qualibet Carectata provision’ tract’ cum non plur’ quam tribus equis in aliquod Mercat’ predict’ ibidem vendend’ im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portat’ quatuor denar’ per diem &amp; pro qualibet Carectata provision’ tract’ cum quatuor equis vel plur’ in aliquod Mercat’ predict’ ibidem vendend’ im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portat’
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:150224:4"/> sex denar’ per diem ac diver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sarum al’ denar’ sum’ de quibuslibet personis que aliqua victualia sive pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vision’ da Mercat’ infra Civit’ <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> predict’ seu eorum aliqua vel aliquod importarent ibidem vendend’ ac per eandem legem sic per eos ille<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>galit’ fact’ iidem Major &amp; Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nit’ ac Cives Civit’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ de facto ordinaver’ quod eedem sepe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral’ denar’ summe solut’ forent ad propr’ opus &amp; usum prefat’ Majoris &amp; Communitat. ac Civium Civit. <hi>London</hi> predict’ ac quod si aliquis in Mercat’ predict’ existen’ cum vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctual’ sive provisionibus suis ibidem vendend’ recusaret sive differret sol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vere respectivas ratas predict’ tunc talis recusans sive differens amot’ fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ret <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>a loco suo in Mercat. predict’ Et ulterius idem Attorn. dict’ Dom. Regis nunc General’ pro eodem Dom. Rege nunc dic’ quod predict’ Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civit. <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> predict. sub solo colore &amp; pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>textu legis predict’ sic per ipsos pro eorum privato lucro &amp; commodo ille<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>galit’ fact. &amp; abs{que} aliquo alio jure Titulo sive Authoritate quibuscun{que} diversas ingentes denar. Summas in toto se attingen. ad quinque mille li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bras per annum per spacium septem annorum post predcit. decimum septi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mum diem <hi>Septembris</hi> Anno vice<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>simo sexto supradicto prox. sequen.
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:150224:4"/> &amp; amplius apud <hi>London</hi> predict. in Paroch. predict. de omnibus Dom. Regis ligeis &amp; subditis ad publica Mercata per totum tempus predict. in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fra Civit. predict. tent. cum victuali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus &amp; provisionibus ibidem vendend. accedentibus erexer. levaver. &amp; exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gi &amp; levari fecerunt &amp; denarios illos ad eorum proprios usus converterunt &amp; disposuerunt in subversionem boni regiminis et gubernac’onis Civitatis predict’ et in magnam oppressionem et depauperac’on. subditor. dict. Dom. Regis nunc ad Mercat. predict’ cum victualibus et provision. suis acce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den. et venien. ad grave dampn. et no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cument. omnium Ligeorum et Subdit. dict Dom. Regis in Augmentac. pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciorum omnium victual. et provision. in Mercatis predict. vendit. ac in dict. Dom. Regis nunc et Corone sue Regie exheredac’on. manifestam ac contra fiduciam in Corpore Corporat. et Politico per Dom. Regem ac Leges hujus Regni <hi>Angl.</hi> reposit’ Et ulte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rus idem Attorn. dicti Dom. Regis nunc General’ pro eodem Domino Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ge nunc dic’ quod ubi Sessio Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>menti Dom. Regis nunc per Proroga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>c’on. tent’ fuit apud <hi>Westm.</hi> in Com. <hi>Middlesex.</hi> super vicesimum pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mum diem <hi>Octobris</hi> Anno Regni dicti Dom. Regis nunc tricesimo se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundo
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:150224:5"/> ac ibidem continuat’ us{que} deci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mum diem <hi>Januar’</hi> tunc prox’ sequen’ ac super eodem decimo die <hi>Januarii</hi> anno regni dict’ Dom. Regis nunc tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cesimo secundo supradict’ apud <hi>West<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minst.</hi> predicti idem Parliamentum Prorogat’ fuit per dict’ Dom. Regem nunc us{que} vicesimum diem tunc In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stantis <hi>Januar.</hi> predict’ Major et Communitas ac Cives Civitat’ <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> predict’ postea scil’ die <hi>Jovis</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cimo tertio die <hi>Januar’</hi> Anno Regni dict’ Dom. Regis nunc tricesimo se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundo supradict’ in eorum Communi Concilio tent’ in Camera <hi>Guihald</hi> Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit’ predict’ viz. in Paroch’ Sancti <hi>Michaelis Bassishaw London</hi> pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. Assemblat’ illicite malitiose ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>visate et seditiose et abs{que} aliqua le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gali authoritate in se assumpser’ ad censend’ et judicand’ dict’ Dom. Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gem nunc et Prorogac’ on’ Parliamen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ti per dict’ Dom. Regem nunc sic fact’ Ac adtunc et ibidem iidem Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor et Communitas ab Cives Civitat. <hi>London</hi> sic in eodem Communi Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cilio Assemblat’ vota et suffragia sua deder’ et ordinaver’ quod quedam Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titio sub nomine Majoris Aldermannum et Commun’ Civit’ <hi>London</hi> in Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>muni Concil. Assemblat’ dicto Dom.
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:150224:5"/> Regi nunc exhibit’ foret in qua qui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Peticone content. fuit quod per predict’ Prorogacon’ Parliamenti pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict’ prosecuco’ Justic’ publice hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jus regni ac preparaco’ <hi>Anglice</hi> the making provision necessar. preser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vacon. dicti Dom. Regis nunc ac e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jus subditorum protestantium recepis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent obstrucon’ <hi>Anglice</hi> Interrupcon’ et iidem Major et Communitas ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves Civitat. <hi>London</hi> predict’ in Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>muni Concilio predict’ sic ut prefertur Assemblat’ illicite malitiose advisate &amp; seditiose &amp; ea intencone quod ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Petitio publicat’ &amp; dispersa fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ret inter subditos dict’ Dom. Regis nunc fideles ad ipsos in opinion’ indu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cend’ quod idem Dominus Rex nunc per Prorogacon’ Parliamenti predict’ publicam Justic’ regni obstruxisset &amp; ad eosdem Subditos dict’ Dom. Regis incitand’ in odium persone dict’ Dom. Regis &amp; gubernacon. in hoc regno stabilit’ &amp; ad perturband’ pacem &amp; tranquillitat’ in hoc Regno <hi>Anglie</hi> adtunc &amp; ibidem ordinaver’ quod ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Petitio sic continen’ seditiosam &amp; scandalosam materiam predict’ im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>press’ foret ac postea scil’ die &amp; An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no ult. supradict’ apud <hi>London</hi> pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict’
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:150224:6"/> in Paroch’ predict’ eandem Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticon. ea intencone quod eadem pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licat’ &amp; dispers’ foret inter subdit’ dict. Dom. Regis nunc ad affectiones suas a dict’ Dom. Rege nunc &amp; gu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bernacon’ sua alienand’ &amp; divertend’ malitiose advisate &amp; seditiose impres<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ser’ &amp; imprimi &amp; publicari fecer’ &amp; causaver’ in contempt’ &amp; scandalum dict’ Dom. Regis nunc ac gubernacon’ sue hujus Regni <hi>Anglie</hi> ac in promo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>con. &amp; excitacon. seditionis &amp; per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turbacon. pacis &amp; tranquilitat’ in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fra hoc regnum <hi>Anglie</hi> &amp; in perni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiosum aliorum dict’ Dom. Regis nunc Subdit’ &amp; Ligeorum exemplum per quod idem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat. Privileg. &amp; Franches. pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict’ fore de seipsis Corpus Corporat’ &amp; Politicum per nomen Majoris &amp; Communitat’ ac Civium Civitat’ <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> forisfecer’ predict’ tamen Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ postea scil’ per tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pus superius in Informacone predict’ specificat’ Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Franches. ill’ super dict’ Dom. Regem nunc usurpaver’ &amp; adhuc usurpant
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:150224:6"/> prout per Informacon. predict’ superi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>us versus eos supponitur. Et hoc idem Attorn’ dict’ Dom. Regis nunc General’ pro eodem Domino Rege nunc parat’ est verificare unde petit’ judicium &amp; quod predict’ Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat’ <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> de premiss, predict’ Convincan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tur ac de Libertat. Privileg. &amp; Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches. ill’ abdicantur &amp; excludantur &amp;c. Et quoad placitum prefat’ Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joris &amp; Communitat’ ac Civium Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ quoad Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat. Privileg. &amp; Franches. pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict. per ipsos superius clamat’ (viz.) ipsos habere Vice-comit’ Civit. &amp; Com. Civit. <hi>London</hi> &amp; Vice-comit’ Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> &amp; nominare &amp; eligere ex seipsis duas personas fore Vice<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comit’ Civit. predict. &amp; Com. ejusdem Civit. &amp; Vicecomit. Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> Ac illos sic nominat. &amp; elect. preficere &amp; constituere Vic’ Civit. predict. &amp; Com. ejusdem Civit. &amp; Vic’ Com. <hi>Midd.</hi> Ac ut Vicecomit’ Civitat’ pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict’ &amp; Com. ejusdem Civitat. ad execucon. et retorn’ omnium Brevi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um Billarum et precept’ Dom. Regis pro administracon. et execucon. Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sticie
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:150224:7"/> infra Civit predict. et Com. ejus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Civit. exequend. faciend. que ad Officium Vic’ faciend. pertinent’ ac ad faciend. et exequend. omnia et sin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gula. alia infra Civit’ predict’ &amp; Com’ ejusdem Civit’ que ad officium Vicecom. faciend’ pertinent ac ut Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cecom. Com. <hi>Middlesex</hi> pro eodem Com. deservitur. ac omnia Brevia Billas &amp; precept’ Dom. Regis infra Com. <hi>Middlesex</hi> pro administracone &amp; execucone Justicie ibidem et exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend’ &amp; retorn’ inde faciend’ que ad Officium Vic’ faciend’ pertinent. supe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rius placitat: Necnon quoad placitum prefat’ Majoris &amp; Communitat’ ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vium Civitat’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ quoad Libertat’ Privileg’ &amp; Franches’ per ipsos superius clamat’ (Viz.) Major dict’ Civitat’ &amp; hujusmodi Alderman’ ejusdem Civitat’ qui Officium Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jorat’ Civit’ illius sustinuer’ ac inde fuer’ dimissi ac tres Alderman’ sen’ Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vit’ predict’ qui diutius in Officio Alderman’ Civit’ predict’ steter’ &amp; onus &amp; Officium Majorat’ Civit’ non sustinuer’ fore Justiciar’ Dom. Regis ad pacem infra Civit’ predict’ conservandum ac ad Session. pacis &amp; placita Corone (Scilicet) talia pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cita Corone qual’ Justiciar’ Dom.
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:150224:7"/> Regis ad pacem conservand’ assign’ ligittime tenere possent infra eandem Civitat’ tenend’ ac ad omnia Felon’ Riot’ Rout’ &amp; Conventicul’ illicit’ infra Civitat’ predict’ inquirend’ au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diend’ &amp; terminand’ superius placitat’ idem Attorn’ Dom. Regis nunc Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral’ qui &amp;c. pet’ licenc’ inde interlo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quend’ coram Dom. Rege usque a die Sancti <hi>Michaelis</hi> in tres sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timanas ubicun{que} &amp;c. Et ei concedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tur’ idem dies dat’ est prefat’ Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor Communitat’ ac Civibus Civit’ <hi>London</hi> predict’ &amp;c.</p>
         </div>
         <div xml:lang="eng" type="version">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:150224:1"/>
            <head>The King against the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>AND the said <hi>Robert Saw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yer</hi> Attorney General of our said Lord the King that now is, who for our Lord the King on this behalf prosecuteth: As to the Plea of the said Major and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, as to the Liberties, Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledges and Franchises afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, by them above claimed, to wit, That they the said Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor, Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> are of themselves one Body Corporate and Politick, in matter, fact and name, by the name of Major and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by the same name to plead and be impleaded, to answer and be answered, as is above pleaded: He the said Attorney General for the said Lord the King saith, That for any thing by the said Major and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, above in pleading al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledged: The said Liberties, Privileges and Franchises ought not to be allowed or adjudged to the same Major and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty, and Citizens of the City
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:150224:2"/> of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid: Neither ought the said Major and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens to be dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged from the premisses in the Information aforesaid speci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied, because he saith, That the Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, from the time where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the memory of Man is not to the contrary, were not a Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy Corporate and Politick, in matter, fact, and name, by the name of Major and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> in manner and form as the said Major and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, above in plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding have alledged: And this the said Attorney General of our said Lord the King that now is for our said Lord the King prays, That it may be enquired of by the Countrey. And the said <hi>Robert Sawyer</hi> At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney General of our said Lord the King that now is, as to the Plea of the said Mayor and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, as to the Liberties, Priviledges and Franchises aforesaid, by them above claimed (to wit) That they the said Mayor and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> are of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves one Body Corporate and Politick in Matter, Fact and Name, by the Name of Mayor and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by the same Name to Plead, and be
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:150224:2"/> Impleaded, to Answer, and be Answered, as is above Pleaded: He further saith, That by any thing by the said Mayor and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore in pleading alledged: The same Liberties, Priviledges and Franchises ought not to be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed and adjudged to the said Mayor and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, neither ought the same Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens to be discharged of the premisses in the Information a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid specified, because by protestation that the Citizens of the same City, from the time whereof the memory of Man is not to the contrary, were not a Body Corporate and Politick in Matter, Fact and Name, by the name of Mayor and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by the same name for all that time have Pleaded, and were Impleaded, and have Answered, and were Answered, and to Plead, and be Impleaded, to Answer, and to be Answered for, by all the time aforesaid have used and accustomed in such manner as the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid above in pleading have alledg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed: Notwithstanding for Plea the said Attorney General of our said Lord the King, for our said Lord the King further saith, That the said Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:150224:3"/> and Citizens of the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid assuming upon themselves to be a Body Corporate and Politick, and by reason thereof to have power and authority to Call and As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>semble themselves together for the making good and whole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>some Laws, Orders and Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances not repugnant nor con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the Laws and Statutes of this Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> for the better rule and government of the City aforesaid, and of the Citizens and Inhabitants of the said City, and for the keeping of the Kings Peace within the said City: The said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der colour and pretence thereof respecting only their own pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate gain and profit, contrary to the confidence reposed in a Body Corporate and Politick by our Lord the King, and the Laws of this Kingdom of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> have assumed an unlawful, and unjust Power and Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty to Levy Money of the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, and Leige-people of our Lord the King that now is, to the proper use of the said Mayor and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, by colour of the Laws or Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances by them in fact ordained and established, without any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Right, Title or Authority whatsoever: And in prosecuti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and Execution of such ille<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gal and unjust Power and Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:150224:3"/> by them so usurped, They the said Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, on <hi>Thursday</hi> the Seventeenth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the Six and Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth Year of the Reign of our said Lord the King that now is, in their Common-Council then held in the Chamber of the <hi>Guild-hall</hi> of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, to wit, in the Parish of St. <hi>Michael Bassishaw, London,</hi> being Assembled together, did make, and publish a certain Law, by them in fact Enacted, for the Levying several Sums of Money of all his Majesties Subjects and Leige-People, as well Free as not Free-men of the said City, and other Forreigners, at the publick Markets held within the City aforesaid, coming thither to sell their Victuals, and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>visions (to wit) of every person for every Horse-load of Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sions, by him brought into any publick Market of the said City, there to be sold, Two Pence by the day, and for every Dosser of Provision brought into any Market aforesaid, there to be sold, One Penny by the day, and for every Cart-load of Provisions drawn with no more then three Horses, brought into any Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket aforesaid, there to be sold, Four Pence by the day, and for every Cart-Load of Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sions drawn with Four Horses or more, brought into any Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket aforesaid, there to be sold,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:150224:4"/> Six-pence by the day, and of divers other Sums of Money of whatsoever persons should bring any Victuals or Provisions to the Markets within the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforesaid, or some of them, or any thing there to be sold, and by the same Law so by them ille<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gally made, the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, in fact have Ordained, That the said several Sums of money should be paid to the proper use and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hoof of them the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid: And that if any person being in the Markets aforesaid with Victuals or Provisions there to be sold, should refuse or defer to pay the respective Rates aforesaid, that then such person so refusing or deferring, should be removed from his place in the said Market. And the said Attorney-General of our said Lord the King that now is further saith, That the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforesaid, under the sole Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour and pretence of the Law aforesaid so by them for their private gain and profit illegally made, and without any other Right, Title or Authority what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soever, divers great Sums of mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney in the whole amounting to 5000 l. yearly by the space of Seven Years after the said Seven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of <hi>September</hi> in the Six and twentieth year aforesaid next
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:150224:4"/> ensuing, and more at <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid in the Parish aforesaid of all the Liege-People and Subjects of our Lord the King, coming to the Publick Markets held for all the before-mentioned time with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the said City, with Provisions and Victuals there to be sold, have exacted, levied, and caused to be exacted and levied, and the same Money they have convert<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and disposed of to their own use, In subversion of the good Rule and Government of the said City, and to the great oppression and impoverishing of the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects of our said Lord the King coming to the said Markets with their Victuals &amp; Provisions, And to the great dammage and hurt of all the Liege-People and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects of our said Lord the King, to the encreasing and raising of the Prices of all Victuals and Provisions sold in the Markets aforesaid: And to the manifest disheriting of our said Lord the King that now is; And contrary to the Confidence reposed in a Body Corporate and Politick by our Lord the King and the Laws of this Realm of <hi>England:</hi> And the said Attorney-General of our said Lord the King that now is, for our said Lord the King fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther saith, That whereas a Ses<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion of Parliament of our Lord the King that now is, was held at <hi>Westminster</hi> in the County of <hi>Middlesex</hi> by Prorogation upon the One and twentieth day of <hi>October,</hi> in the Two and Thirtieth
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:150224:5"/> Year of his said now Majesties Reign, And there continued un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>till the 10th day of <hi>January</hi> then next ensuing, and upon the same tenth day of <hi>January,</hi> in the two and thirtieth Year of his said Majesties Reign, at <hi>Westminster</hi> aforesaid, the same Parliament was Prorogued by our Lord the King that now is, until the 20th day of the then Instant of <hi>January,</hi> The said Mayor and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid afterwards, to wit, On <hi>Thursday</hi> the Thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of <hi>January,</hi> in the two and thirtieth Year of his said now Majesties Reign, in their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Council held in their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil Chamber at <hi>Guild-hall</hi> of the City aforesaid, to wit, in the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rish of St. <hi>Michael Bassishaw, Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforesaid, being Assembled, did unlawfully, maliciously, ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>visedly and sediciously, and with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any Legal Authority assume upon themselves to censure and judge our said Lord the King that now is, and the Prorogati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the Parliament so made by our said Lord the King that now is; And then and there they the said Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>London,</hi> so Assembled in their Common Council, did then Vote and Ordain, That a certain Petition under the Name of the Mayor, Aldermen and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons of the City of <hi>London</hi> in the Common Council Assem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled, should be exhibited to our
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:150224:5"/> said Lord the King that now is, in which Petition there was con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, That by the said Proroga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Parliament aforesaid, the prosecution of the publick Justice of this Kingdom, and the making provision necessary for the preservation of our said Lord the King that now is, and of his Protestant Subjects, recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved interruption, and the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, in the Common Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil aforesaid, so as aforesaid As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sembled, unlawfully, malicious<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, advisedly, and seditiously, and to the intent that the same Petition might be published and dispersed abroad amongst his now Majesties faithful Subjects, to induce them into the opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, That our said Lord the King that now is, by Proroga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Parliament aforesaid had obstructed the publick Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stice of the Kingdom, and to incite the same Subjects of our said Lord the King that now is, to the hatred of the Person of our said Lord the King, and of his Government Establish'd in this Kingdom, and to disturb the Peace and Tranquility of this Kingdom of <hi>England;</hi> they then and there did Ordain, That the same Petition containing the se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditious and scandalous matter a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid should be Imprinted: And afterwards, to wit, The day and year last aforesaid at
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:150224:6"/>
               <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, in the Parish a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, the same Petition to the intent that the same might be published and dispersed a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst the Subjects of our said Lord the King that now is, to alienate and divert their affecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons from our said Lord the King that now is, and from his Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, they malitiously, ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>visedly and seditiously did Print, and cause to be Imprinted and Published to the contempt and scandal of our said Lord the King that now is, and of his Government of this Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> and to the promo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting and raising of Sedition, and disturbance of the Peace and Tranquility within this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of <hi>England,</hi> and to the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nicious example of others his Majesties Subjects and Leige-people; by which the said May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or and Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said have forfeited the Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchises afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, to be of themselves a Body Corporate and Politick, by the Name of Mayor and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London:</hi> Yet the aforesaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, afterwards (to wit) by all the time in the Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion aforesaid specified, have usurped upon our Lord the King, and yet do usurp those Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Priviledges and Franchises,
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:150224:6"/> so as by the Information afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said against them is supposed: And this the said Attorney Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral of our said Lord the King that now is, for our said Lord the King is ready to aver, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he prays Judgment, and that the said Mayor and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> may be convicted of the premisses aforesaid, and be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded from, and forejudged their Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchises, &amp;c. And as to the Plea of the said Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid: As to the Liberties, Priviledges and Franchises aforesaid by them before claimed (to wit) That they have Sheriffs of the City, and County of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> and a Sheriff of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>Middlesex,</hi> and that they Nominate and Chuse out of themselves two persons to be Sheriffs of the City aforesaid, and County of the said City and She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riff of the County of <hi>Middlesex;</hi> And to make and constitute those persons so Nominated and Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted Sheriffs of the City afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, and of the County of the said City, and Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middlesex:</hi> And as Sheriffs of the City aforesaid, and County of the said City, to Execute and Return all the Writs, Bills and Precepts of our Lord the King, for the Administration and Execution of Justice within
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:150224:7"/> the said City, and the County of the said City, to be executed and done, which do appertain to the Office of a Sheriff to be done: And to do and execute all and singular other things with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the said City and County of the said City, which appertain to the Office of a Sheriff to be done: And as Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middlesex</hi> to serve for the same County; And to Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute and make Retorns of all the Writs, Bills and Prccepts of our Lord the King, within the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>Middlesex,</hi> for the Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stration and Execution of Justice there to be executed and retur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, appertaining to the Office of a Sheriff to be done before pleaded. And also as to the Plea of the said Mayor and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforesaid, as to the Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Priviledges, and Franchises by them before claimed (to wit) The Mayor of the said City, and such Aldermen of the same City who had born the Office of May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or of that City, and from thence were dismissed: And Three Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nior Aldermen of the said City, who had stood longer in the Office of an Alderman, and had never born the Burthen and Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice of Mayor of the said City, should be Justices of our Lord the King to keep the Peace with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the City; And at the Sessions of the Peace and Pleas of the Crown (to wit) such Pleas of
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:150224:7"/> the Crown as the Justices of our Lord the King assigned to keep the Peace, might Lawfully hold within the said City to be held, And to enquire, hear, and deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine of all Felonies, Riots, Routs, and unlawful Conventi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles within the said City before pleaded: The said Attorney General of our Lord the King, who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> prays License to Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parle before our Lord the King until from the day of St. <hi>Michael</hi> in Three weeks wheresoever, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and it is granted unto him. The same day is given to the said Major, Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:150224:8"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>